Although the Seventh Prince is at the border,
일곱 번째 왕자이긴 하지만 국경에 있어
he has always been concerned about your health, Your Highness.
그 사람은 늘 걱정이었어 건강에 대해서요, 전하.
These are the border specialties
국경 특산품은 다음과 같습니다
that His Highness had people prepare.
전하께서는 사람들에게 준비를 시키셨다고 합니다.
Hongteng fruit and mistletoe—
홍텡과일과 겨우살이—
they are foods beneficial to the fetus.
태아에게 유익한 식품입니다.
He specifically asked me, upon returning to the capital,
그는 나에게 구체적으로 물었다. 수도로 돌아오자마자
to bring them to you.
그것들을 당신에게 가져오려고요.
The physician warned me
의사가 나에게 경고했어
not to eat food of unknown origin.
원산지를 알 수 없는 음식을 먹지 말 것.
There are too many things to dispose of in my mansion every day
버릴 것들이 너무 많아 매일 내 맨션에서
You should take these things
너는 이것들을 가져가야 해
back exactly as they are.
정확히 그대로 돌아왔습니다.
Your Highness,
전하,
this is a token of the Seventh Prince's affection.
이것은 토큰이다 일곱째 왕자의 애정.
You...
당신은...
I think too much during my pregnancy.
임신 중에는 생각이 너무 많아요.
If you truly care about me,
정말로 나에게 관심이 있다면
don't come here anymore.
더 이상 여기에 오지 마세요.
See the guest out.
손님을 만나보세요.
I will take my leave.
나는 떠날 것이다.
I know a little bit about medicine.
나는 의학에 대해 조금 알고 있습니다.
The things the Seventh Prince sent
일곱 번째 왕자가 보낸 것들
are indeed good things.
참으로 좋은 일들입니다.
Why didn't you accept them, Your Highness?
왜 받아들이지 않으셨나요, 전하?
Zhao Che
자오 체
is now a hidden threat to my father
이제 내 아버지에 대한 숨겨진 위협이 되었어요
and the Thirteenth Prince.
그리고 열세 번째 왕자.
Since I belong to the Thirteenth Prince now,
내가 속한 이래로 이제 13번째 왕자,
I naturally have to draw a clear line with him.
당연히 명확한 선을 그어야지 그와 함께.
Go.
가다.
Light the incense left by Jia Meng for me.
Jia Meng이 나에게 남긴 향에 불을 붙여주세요.
Yes.
예.
Li Yan,
리얀,
you're here?
당신은 여기 있나요?
You know what?
그거 알아?
I will soon be the Princess Protector of the State.
나는 곧 국가의 공주 수호자가 되십시오.
I will be more noble
나는 더 고귀해질 거야
than ever before.
그 어느 때보다.
What you couldn't give our child,
우리 아이에게 줄 수 없었던 것,
I will make it up to him double.
나는 그에게 두 배의 보상을 해 줄 것이다.
[REBIRTH]
[환생]
[Episode 30]
[30화]
Faceless God, please grant me strength,
얼굴 없는 신이시여, 제게 힘을 주소서,
let Great Yong and Great Yan fight again,
Great Yong과 Great Yan이 다시 싸우게 해주세요
and make sure Zhao Che dies at the border!
그리고 Zhao Che가 국경에서 죽도록 하세요!
The Faceless God has granted your wish.
얼굴 없는 신이 당신의 소원을 들어주었습니다.
Really?
정말?
Yes.
예.
I have more good news for you.
좋은 소식이 더 있습니다.
Jia Meng has already taken action in Ximeng.
Jia Meng은 이미 조치를 취했습니다. 시멍에서.
The land and black gold mines of Ximeng
Ximeng의 토지와 흑금 광산
will all belong to you.
모두 당신의 것입니다.
By then, even if Zhao Che doesn't die,
그때쯤이면 조철이 죽지 않더라도
Father won't even spare him another glance.
아버지도 안 그럴 거야. 그에게 한 번만 더 눈길을 주세요.
You will become
너는
the only heir to the throne in his heart.
그의 마음속에 있는 유일한 왕위 계승자.
After I take over Ximeng,
내가 Ximeng을 인수한 후,
I'll ask Father
아버지께 여쭤볼게요
to kill Zhao Che!
조체를 죽이려고!
Isn't he just good at fighting wars?
그 사람은 전쟁을 잘하는 것 아닌가요?
Father will no longer need him by then.
그때쯤이면 아버지는 더 이상 그 사람을 필요로 하지 않을 것입니다.
And Great Yong will no longer need him either!
그리고 그레이트 용 더 이상 그 사람이 필요하지 않을 것입니다!
Sister Chun.
춘 언니.
If I become the Crown Prince,
내가 왕세자가 된다면
I will make you the Princess Protector of the State.
내가 너를 만들어줄게 국가의 수호자 공주.
I want everyone to crawl at your feet,
모두가 당신 발 밑으로 기어가길 바라요
look up to your beauty,
너의 아름다움을 우러러봐
worship you,
당신을 숭배합니다
and submit to you.
그리고 당신에게 제출하십시오.
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
These...
이것들은...
are probably the names of the brothers still in Qingshan Manor.
아마 형제들의 이름일 거야 아직 Qingshan Manor에 있어요.
After you left,
당신이 떠난 후,
Qingshan Manor dealt with a group of Moon Guards.
칭산 매너 Moon Guard 그룹을 상대했습니다.
Some brothers wanted to escape to survive,
일부 형제들은 생존을 위해 탈출을 원했고,
but...
하지만...
they were all dealt with by my grandfather and Lord Zhan.
그 사람들은 다 처리됐어 나의 할아버지와 잔(Zhan) 경이 만든 것입니다.
Right?
오른쪽?
Once a person of Qingshan Manor,
한때 Qingshan Manor의 사람,
always a person of Qingshan Manor.
항상 Qingshan Manor의 사람입니다.
This is the rule of Qingshan Manor.
이것이 Qingshan Manor의 규칙입니다.
What are you doing there?
거기서 뭐하는거야?
What are you hiding?
당신은 무엇을 숨기고 있습니까?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
Yue Yong, Yue Zeng?
Yue Yong, Yue Zeng?
What is this list?
이 목록은 무엇입니까?
These are the names Young Master chose for the child.
이름은 다음과 같습니다 젊은 스승님이 아이를 위해 선택하셨습니다.
Shiyi!
시이!
What child?
무슨 아이?
These are some names Young Master asked me to look up
이것들은 몇몇 이름이다 젊은 스승님이 나에게 찾아보라고 하셨습니다
and search for.
검색해 보세요.
He said they are options for your future children.
옵션이라고 하더라구요 미래의 아이들을 위해.
Yue Shiyi,
Yue Shiyi,
what nonsense are you talking about?
무슨 말도 안되는 소리를 하는 거야?
Young Master,
젊은 스승님,
don't be shy.
부끄러워하지 마세요.
If we don't tell Lady Chu,
Lady Chu에게 말하지 않으면
you won't be able to explain it.
당신은 그것을 설명할 수 없을 것이다.
Why do I feel something's off?
뭔가 이상하다는 느낌이 드는 이유는 무엇입니까?
Most of the names
대부분의 이름
on this list are male.
이 목록에는 남성이 있습니다.
There is a female name.
여자 이름이 있습니다.
Look,
보세요,
this is the one the Young Master picked.
이것이 Young Master가 선택한 것입니다.
Yuegui?
위에구이?
Right.
오른쪽.
The Young Master likes
젊은 스승이 좋아하는 것
the name Yuegui the most.
Yuegui라는 이름이 가장 많습니다.
He hopes you will be together forever
그는 당신이 영원히 함께하길 바라요
and have children soon.
그리고 곧 아이를 갖게 됩니다.
Shiyi!
시이!
Let's go out for a walk.
산책하러 나가자.
[Chu's Mansion]
[추의 저택]
It is this tree.
바로 이 나무입니다.
Yuegui
위에구이
is the name of this tree?
이 나무 이름이 뭔가요?
Not a child's name?
아이 이름이 아닌가요?
This kind of tree cannot be seen
이런 나무는 볼 수 없어
in Great Yong and Biantang.
그레이트용(Great Yong)과 비안탕(Biantang)에서.
It can only grow in Ximeng
Ximeng에서만 자랄 수 있어요
and the continent further west.
그리고 대륙은 더 서쪽에 있습니다.
It may be slender now,
지금은 날씬해졌을지도 모르지만,
but in a few years,
하지만 몇 년 안에,
it will be big enough to shade the whole yard.
충분히 클 거야 마당 전체에 그늘을 드리우려고요.
We can enjoy the shade in summer.
여름에는 그늘을 즐길 수 있습니다.
It will bloom in autumn,
가을에 꽃이 피겠죠,
and the fragrance of laurel will fill the air.
그리고 향수 월계수 잎이 공기를 가득 채울 것입니다.
When Ximeng is at peace again
Ximeng이 다시 평화로워지면
and we finally have time,
드디어 시간이 생겼어요
we can enjoy tea and flowers under this tree
우리는 차와 꽃을 즐길 수 있어요 이 나무 아래
and eat hot pot.
그리고 냄비를 먹어요.
You just said
방금 말했지
Yuegui is the name of this tree.
Yuegui는 이 나무의 이름입니다.
Then what are Yue Yong and Yue Zeng?
그렇다면 Yue Yong과 Yue Zeng은 무엇입니까?
They wouldn't
그들은 그렇지 않을 거야
really be children's names, right?
정말 아이들 이름이겠죠?
What's wrong with you?
왜 그래?
I never thought
전혀 생각해본 적 없어
I would spend a day like this with you.
나는 당신과 함께 이런 하루를 보낼 것입니다.
I made a plate of pastries today— a rather rare thing for me.
오늘은 페이스트리 한 접시를 만들었어요- 나에게는 꽤 드문 일이다.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Try some.
시도해 보세요.
How are they? Do they taste good?
그들은 어때요? 맛이 좋나요?
Yes.
예.
Taste good.
맛이 좋다.
Well...
음...
Lady Chu,
추 부인,
it's your first time making pastries.
페이스트리를 만드는 건 처음이군요.
It's normal
정상이야
for them to taste bad.
맛이 나빠지도록.
It's not my first time.
이번이 처음이 아닙니다.
Before in Qingshan Manor,
Qingshan Manor에 오기 전,
when I made them for Zhuge Yue,
내가 Zhuge Yue를 위해 만들었을 때,
they were like this too.
그들도 이랬다.
Ask him.
그에게 물어보세요.
Is it good?
좋은가요?
Yes.
예.
It's the fruit's problem.
문제는 과일이다.
No.
아니요.
The fruit is sour and bitter.
열매는 신맛과 쓴맛이 난다.
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
I heard from the kitchen
부엌에서 들었어
that recently, the sour fruit trees in Ximeng
그 최근에, Ximeng의 신 과일나무들
have caught a strange epidemic.
이상한 전염병에 걸렸어요.
So the palace stopped buying them.
그래서 궁전은 그것들을 사는 것을 중단했습니다.
This is the last batch.
이것이 마지막 배치입니다.
It seems
그런 것 같아
this batch can't be used either.
이 배치도 사용할 수 없습니다.
Epidemic?
감염병 유행?
Excuse me!
실례합니다!
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
The road ahead is blocked.
앞길이 막혀있습니다.
These people are gathering in the center of the city,
이런 사람들이 모여있어요 도시 중심부에
asking for some holy water.
성수를 달라고 합니다.
It seems
그런 것 같아
our carriage
우리 마차
can't get through for a while.
한동안 통과할 수 없습니다.
Let's split up.
헤어지자.
You and Xiao Ran go to the orchard outside the city.
당신과 샤오란은 과수원으로 갑니다 도시 밖에서.
I'll go over there and see what happened.
내가 거기 가서 무슨 일이 일어났는지 확인해 볼게요.
Look at these sand date trees.
이 모래대추나무를 보세요.
The infected ones
감염된 사람들
are rotting all over.
온통 썩어가고 있어요.
How could this happen?
어떻게 이런 일이 일어날 수 있습니까?
And the color of the soil
그리고 흙의 색깔
is a bit strange.
좀 이상해요.
The soil in Ximeng is mostly red,
Ximeng의 토양은 대부분 빨간색입니다.
but look at this soil—
그런데 이 흙을 좀 보세요—
it's a bit green.
약간 녹색이에요.
Up ahead, it should be the water source for this orchard.
앞으로는 그래야 해 이 과수원의 수원지.
Let's go and take a look.
가서 살펴보자.
Don't you think
그렇게 생각하지 않나요
these birds and beasts died strangely?
이 새들과 짐승들이 이상하게 죽었어요?
The river is obviously polluted.
강은 분명히 오염되었습니다.
This seems to be
This seems to be
some kind of sacrifice.
인 것 같아요
It's time for the holy water.
일종의 희생.
Sir.
성수를 마실 시간입니다.
Sir,
선생님.
what are you going to get?
선생님,
The holy water, of course.
당신은 무엇을 얻을 예정입니까?
The holy water?
물론 성수죠.
What is holy water?
성수?
The holy water is a cure-all.
성수란 무엇인가?
As long as we believe in the Saintess devoutly,
성수는 만병통치약이다.
she will give us holy water.
우리가 성녀를 믿는 한 경건하게,
I heard it can also cure the crabapple trees' disease.
그녀는 우리에게 성수를 줄 것입니다.
Stop talking. Let's go!
치료도 된다고 들었는데 게사과나무병.
There won't be any holy water left if we're late.
말을 중지하세요. 갑시다!
Thank you. Thank you.
성수는 하나도 남지 않을 거야 우리가 늦으면.
And me!
감사합니다. 감사합니다.
Me!
그리고 나!
Lady Chu,
나!
I'll go ahead and take a look.
추 부인,
Don't push. Come on.
제가 가서 살펴보겠습니다.
There's one more bottle.
밀지 마세요. 어서 해봐요.
Please!
한 병 더 있어요.
I want some too!
제발!
Me too!
나도 좀 갖고 싶어!
Thank you.
저도요!
I got it!
감사합니다.
Lady Chu, you're looking for someone?
알겠어요!
Nothing.
Lady Chu, 누군가를 찾고 있나요?
What did you get?
아무것도 아님.
It seems that the crabapple trees outside the city have got a strange disease.
무엇을 얻었나요?
This holy water can cure them.
밖에 게사과나무가 있는 것 같아요 도시에 이상한 질병이 생겼어요.
I heard from those people
이 성수는 그들을 치료할 수 있습니다.
that this Saintess
그 사람들한테서 들었어
was chosen by some Faceless God.
이 성녀는
And this holy water is also bestowed by the Faceless God.
얼굴없는 신에게 선택받았습니다.
I got it.
그리고 이 성수도 부여됩니다. 얼굴 없는 신에 의해.
This is a panacea
알겠어요.
called Kuji Grass.
이것이 만병통치약이다
It can cure many common poisons.
구지그라스라고 불린다.
If I'm not mistaken,
그것은 많은 일반적인 독을 치료할 수 있습니다.
the water source near the orchard has been polluted,
내가 착각한 것이 아니라면,
and this medicine
과수원 근처의 수원 오염되었습니다.
is used to detoxify the water.
그리고 이 약
So the river water
물을 해독하는 데 사용됩니다.
was poisoned?
그럼 강물은
It should be,
중독됐어?
but it's probably not a fatal poison.
but it's probably not a fatal poison.
The people also drink the river water, but they are fine.
하지만 아마도 치명적인 독은 아닐 겁니다.
Only some livestock and fruit trees were affected.
사람들도 강물을 마시고, 하지만 괜찮아요.
What exactly is the Faceless God?
일부 가축과 과일나무만 영향을 받았습니다.
Does anyone know?
얼굴 없는 신이란 정확히 무엇인가?
Faceless God?
아는 사람 있나요?
Back in the day,
얼굴 없는 신?
I, Wang Shi'er, went to the southern and western regions
예전에는
to rob tombs.
나 Wang Shi'er가 갔다. 남부 및 서부 지역
But how come I have never heard
무덤을 털다.
of this god without a face?
그런데 왜 난 한 번도 들어본 적이 없지
Young Master Zhuge.
얼굴 없는 신이요?
What happened?
젊은 스승 제게.
Great Yan has sent a visiting card,
무슨 일이에요?
saying the King of Great Yan is coming to Ximeng to offer congratulations.
대연왕이 오신다고 하네 Ximeng에게 축하 인사를 전했습니다.
He is already outside Ximengcheng.
그는 이미 Ximengcheng 밖에 있습니다.
He will enter the city tomorrow to pay his respects.
그는 내일 그 도시에 들어갈 것이다 그의 존경을 표하기 위해.
[We are pleased to hear of the promulgation of Ximeng's new policy, which reforms the old and introduces the new.]
[우리는 Ximeng의 새로운 정책이 발표되었다는 소식을 듣고 기쁘게 생각합니다. 오래된 것을 개혁하고 새로운 것을 도입하는 것입니다.]
[With wise strategy guiding the state and benevolent governance benefiting the people, this is truly a blessing for Ximeng and its citizens.]
[국가를 지도하는 현명한 전략과 선량한 통치로 사람들에게 이익이 되는 것은 Ximeng과 그 시민들에게 참으로 축복입니다.]
[Great Yan and Ximeng have long shared cordial relations. We now wish to partake in your virtuous transformation and contribute to this grand endeavor.]
[Great Yan과 Ximeng은 오랫동안 따뜻한 관계를 공유해 왔습니다. 이제 우리는 귀하의 선한 변화에 참여하고 이 위대한 노력에 기여하고 싶습니다.]
[We have sent our sincere congratulations along with a modest token of goodwill, humbly hoping you will accept it.]
[진심으로 축하드리며, 소박한 증표를 보내드렸습니다. 선의의 마음으로, 당신이 이를 받아들이기를 겸손히 바랍니다.]
[May Ximeng's national fortune endure for generations,]
[Ximeng의 국운이 여러 세대에 걸쳐 지속되기를 바랍니다.]
[and may Your Majesty and the Queen enjoy peace, health, and prosperity. Yan Xun, King of Great Yan, respectfully bows in salute.]
[폐하와 여왕께서 평화와 건강, 번영을 누리시기를 빕니다. 대연왕 안순이 정중하게 절을 한다.]
Congratulations, King and Queen Ximeng,
축하합니다, 시멍 국왕과 왕비
on your new policy.
당신의 새로운 정책에 대해.
My arrival is a bit abrupt.
나의 도착은 약간 갑작스럽다.
Please don't take offense.
화를 내지 마십시오.
King of Great Yan, you have come a long way
대연왕(大燕王), 먼 길을 오셨어요
to congratulate the Queen and me.
여왕과 나를 축하하기 위해.
Of course we won't take offense.
물론 우리는 화를 내지 않을 것입니다.
However, King of Great Yan,
그러나 대연왕은
next time you should send someone with a visiting card in advance,
다음에 누군가를 보내야 할 때 사전에 방문카드를 가지고
so that the Queen and I
그래서 여왕님과 나
can prepare a proper reception.
적절한 수신을 준비할 수 있습니다.
No need.
필요하지 않습니다.
I brought some gifts for Queen Ximeng.
나는 Ximeng 여왕에게 선물을 가져 왔습니다.
Chu.
추.
This is black jade from the peak
이건 정상에서 온 흑옥이야
of Mount Huihui in Great Yan.
Great Yan의 Huihui 산의.
It was formed by the hot springs at the foot of Mount Huihui
온천수로 인해 형성됐어요 회희산 기슭에서
washing over it for hundreds of years.
수백년 동안 그것을 씻어내세요.
It can be used to make an imperial seal.
황실 인장을 만드는 데 사용할 수 있습니다.
I brought it
내가 가져왔어
to congratulate you
축하드립니다
for finally realizing your long-held wish
오랫동안 간직해 온 소원을 마침내 실현한 것 같아
of freeing the slaves and stopping the war.
노예를 해방시키다 그리고 전쟁을 멈추세요.
This
이
is the finest white fox fur from Great Yan.
최고급 흰여우 모피입니다 그레이트 얀에서.
The Snowy Region Tribe of Great Yan guards the northern border.
설지방 대연족 북쪽 국경을 지키고 있습니다.
The weather there is extremely cold.
그곳의 날씨는 매우 춥습니다.
They have been using animal fur to make coats
동물털을 사용해왔네요 코트를 만들려고
for warmth since ancient times.
예로부터 따뜻함을 위해.
But only the leader of the tribe
하지만 부족의 지도자만이
is entitled to use the white fox fur.
흰 여우 모피를 사용할 자격이 있습니다.
Ximeng has long, harsh winters
Ximeng의 겨울은 길고 혹독합니다
that can last up to 5 or 6 months.
최대 5~6개월까지 지속될 수 있습니다.
These furs
이 모피
are enough to last you for several winters.
당신을 지속시키기에 충분합니다 여러 겨울 동안.
This is a dust-gold armor from Great Yan.
이것은 Great Yan의 먼지 금 갑옷입니다.
It looks soft,
부드러워 보이는데요,
but it is invulnerable to all weapons.
하지만 모든 무기에는 무적입니다.
It is perfect for you to wear on the battlefield.
그것은 당신에게 완벽합니다 전장에서 입기 위해.
This is blood lingzhi from Great Yan.
대연의 혈영지입니다.
It can cure all diseases and prolong life.
모든 질병을 치료하고 생명을 연장할 수 있습니다.
Chu.
추.
There is one more gift
선물이 하나 더 있어요
that I sent to the horse ranch of Ximeng.
내가 Ximeng의 말 목장에 보냈던 것입니다.
Chu,
추,
I promised you
약속했어
that I would take you to see the Huolei horses on Mount Huihui.
내가 당신을 보러 데려갈 거라고 회회산의 화레이(Huolei) 말.
I picked 50 of them this time,
이번에는 50개를 골랐어요
all the finest from Great Yan...
Great Yan의 최고급 제품을 모두...
Yan Xun.
옌쉰.
Come with me.
나와 함께 가자.
I have something to talk to you about.
당신에게 할 얘기가 있어요.
Yan Xun.
옌쉰.
How is...
어때요...
everything in Great Yan?
Great Yan의 모든 것?
Everything is fine, of course.
물론 모든 것이 괜찮습니다.
In the battle of Longyin Pass,
용음관 전투에서
Great Yan suffered heavy losses
Great Yan은 큰 손실을 입었습니다
and was severely weakened.
그리고 심하게 약해졌습니다.
It's already a bitterly cold place.
벌써부터 몹시 추운 곳이군요.
Over the past two years,
지난 2년 동안
the people have been exhausted from military service.
사람들 군 복무로 지쳤습니다.
I'm afraid they can no longer bear
안타깝지만 그들은 더 이상 참을 수 없을 것 같아요
any more extortionate taxes and levies.
더 이상 부당한 세금과 부과금을 부과하지 마십시오.
Your treasury's situation can't be good.
재무부의 상황은 좋지 않을 것입니다.
Plus, with the disastrous defeat of Great Yan,
게다가 처참한 패배로 대연의
what you lost
무엇을 잃었어?
was not only your Black Eagle Army,
당신의 검은 독수리 군대뿐만 아니라
but also the Great Yan army
뿐만 아니라 Great Yan 군대도
recruited from various tribes.
다양한 부족에서 모집됩니다.
Nowadays,
요즘에는
the tribe elders of Great Yan
대연 부족의 장로들
must be complaining about you.
당신에 대해 불평해야합니다.
If you are even slightly careless,
조금이라도 부주의하다면
they may turn against you.
그들은 당신에게 등을 돌릴 수도 있습니다.
Right?
오른쪽?
You're right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
So my trip here
그래서 내 여행은 여기로
is to form an alliance with Ximeng.
Ximeng과 동맹을 맺는 것입니다.
Whether what you said is true or not,
당신이 말한 것이 사실이든 아니든,
you should know better than I do
당신은 나보다 더 잘 알겠지
that Great Yan is now facing both internal turmoil and external threats.
그 Great Yan은 이제 두 가지를 모두 직면하고 있습니다. 내부 혼란과 외부 위협.
An alliance with Ximeng
Ximeng과의 동맹
is the only and best option.
유일하고 최선의 선택입니다.
I used to
나는
regard Great Yan as my hometown
Great Yan을 내 고향으로 여기세요
and treat you and the people of Great Yan
당신과 Great Yan의 사람들을 대접하겠습니다
as my family.
내 가족으로서.
If you still have any sense left,
아직 감각이 남아 있다면
you should do as you said.
당신이 말한 대로 해야 합니다.
Let's not
하지 말자
talk about anything else.
다른 것에 대해 이야기하십시오.
They hugged!
그들은 포옹했습니다!
They actually hugged?
실제로 포옹했다고요?
This is too much.
이건 너무해요.
Isn't this bullying our Young Master?
이건 우리 젊은 스승님을 괴롭히는 것 아닙니까?
Yan Xun!
옌쉰!
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I lost my composure.
나는 평정심을 잃었습니다.
King Ximeng,
시멍왕,
the Queen and I were catching up
여왕과 나는 따라잡고 있었어
and talked a bit too much.
그리고 말을 좀 많이 했어요.
I hope you
바랍니다
will not take offense.
화를 내지 않을 것입니다.
Xing,
싱,
the palace is having the bluestone paths repaired today.
궁전은 가지고있다 오늘 수리된 블루스톤 길.
It's hard to walk.
걷기가 힘들다.
Let me carry you back.
내가 당신을 다시 데려다 드리겠습니다.
And now he's carrying her?
그런데 지금 그 사람이 그녀를 안고 있다고요?
Young Master won!
영 마스터가 승리했습니다!
Are you jealous?
당신은 질투합니까?
It is only natural for me
나에게는 자연스러운 일이야
to carry my queen.
내 여왕을 데려가려고.
Take a guess—
추측해 보세요—
why did Yan Xun come to Ximeng?
Yan Xun은 왜 Ximeng에 왔나요?
Great Yan suffered heavy losses in the battle with Biantang.
Great Yan은 큰 손실을 입었습니다. 비안탕과의 전투에서
The unity of Great Yan
Great Yan의 단결
was maintained by Yan Xun's sheer force.
Yan Xun의 강력한 힘에 의해 유지되었습니다.
After all this turmoil,
이 모든 혼란 끝에
I'm afraid their internal affairs have become unstable.
그들의 내부 문제가 두렵습니다 불안정해졌습니다.
On top of that, with Great Yong posing an external threat,
게다가 그레이트 용과 함께 외부 위협을 가하고 있어
I think
내 생각엔
he came to Ximeng this time
이번에는 Ximeng에 왔어요
to seek an alliance
동맹을 맺으려고
in order to ease pressure on Great Yan.
Great Yan에 대한 압력을 완화하기 위해.
We think alike on this.
우리는 이것에 대해 비슷하게 생각합니다.
It's just that...
그게 바로 그거야...
What?
무엇?
Yan Xun's true purpose
Yan Xun의 진정한 목적
shouldn't be that simple.
그렇게 단순해서는 안 됩니다.
Here you are.
여기 있어요.
Enjoy your meal.
식사를 즐기십시오.
Waiter!
웨이터!
Officers.
장교.
The usual.
평소.
Coming right up!
바로 올라오네요!
Did you see the document?
문서를 보셨나요?
What does it say, bro?
무슨 뜻이에요, 형제?
They found another new mine.
그들은 또 다른 새로운 광산을 발견했습니다.
North of Mount Heihe,
헤이허산 북쪽,
the entire mountain range will be sealed off.
산맥 전체 봉인됩니다.
This is huge.
이것은 엄청납니다.
Now,
이제,
we will have to
we will have to
be busy for a while again.
해야 할 것 같아
Here are the dishes!
당분간 또 바쁘다.
Officers.
여기 요리가 있습니다!
Enjoy.
장교.
Wine for sale!
즐기다.
Officers.
와인 판매!
My caravan and I are new here.
장교.
We were planning to pass through Mount Heihe
나와 내 캐러밴은 여기에 처음 왔습니다.
to do tea business in the south,
우리는 계획하고 있었다 헤이허산을 통과하려면
but we found the road blocked.
남쪽에서 차 장사를 하려고
We happened to hear you mention this,
하지만 우리는 길이 막힌 것을 발견했어요.
so we came to ask about it.
우연히 당신이 이에 대해 언급하는 것을 들었습니다.
Well...
그래서 우리는 그것에 대해 물어보러 왔습니다.
This money is for you to buy some drinks.
음...
Please show us a clear path.
이 돈은 당신이 음료수를 살 돈입니다.
Miss,
명확한 길을 보여주세요.
you're obviously not a local.
아가씨,
They're mining in Mount Heihe recently.
당신은 분명히 현지인이 아닙니다.
The main road is definitely impassable.
그들은 최근 헤이허산에서 채굴을 하고 있습니다.
This puts us in a difficult position.
주요 도로는 확실히 지나갈 수 없습니다.
If we can't go through Mount Heihe,
이것이 우리를 어려운 입장에 놓이게 합니다.
we'll have to detour at least 100 li.
헤이허산을 통과할 수 없다면
If the goods are delayed,
적어도 100리를 우회해야 합니다.
we will be stuck with them.
상품이 지연되면
Miss,
우리는 그들과 함께 갇힐 것입니다.
don't worry about that.
아가씨,
Although the main road is blocked,
그것에 대해 걱정하지 마십시오.
aren't there small paths?
주요 도로가 막혀 있지만
You're lucky you met
작은 길이 없나요?
us two officers today.
만나서 다행이야
For ordinary people,
오늘 우리 두 장교.
it's not so easy to find a way
일반 사람들의 경우
into the mountain.
길을 찾는 건 그리 쉽지 않아
There have always been
산으로.
a few paths in the mountains used by hunters.
항상
A large group definitely couldn't get through,
산속의 몇 가지 길 사냥꾼이 사용합니다.
but for a caravan like yours,
대규모 그룹 확실히 통과할 수 없었어요
it's absolutely no problem.
하지만 당신과 같은 캐러밴에게는
That's great.
전혀 문제 없습니다.
Could you please show us here
훌륭해요.
which path we should take?
여기를 보여주시겠어요
This road
우리는 어떤 길을 택해야 할까요?
is definitely a dead end.
이 길
But this one...
확실히 막다른 골목이다.
Thank you for solving my problem, officers.
하지만 이건...
Miss.
내 문제를 해결해 주셔서 감사합니다. 장교.
Don't leave in a hurry.
미스
Right.
서둘러 떠나지 마십시오.
May I know... how old you are?
오른쪽.
Spare me, sir.
알 수 있을까요... 몇 살이신가요?
I didn't know she was already taken.
살려주세요.
It's a misunderstanding.
나는 그녀가 이미 데려갔는지 몰랐어요.
Get lost!
그것은 오해입니다.
Bro, wait for me!
길을 잃다!
Your Majesty.
형, 기다려요!
Although the black gold mine is adjacent to Great Yan,
폐하.
within a distance of under 200 miles
검은 금광이기는 하지만 Great Yan에 인접해 있습니다.
lie the Mount Ximin range and the Blackwater River Valley.
200마일 이내
The terrain is treacherous.
시민산 산맥이 있다 그리고 블랙워터 리버 밸리.
Only if we
지형은 위험합니다.
take a small group of men
take a small group of men
to detour through Ximeng territory,
소수의 남자 그룹을 데려가세요
can we quietly
Ximeng 영토를 우회하여
seize the mine entrance.
조용히 할 수 있을까
Detour through Ximeng territory?
광산 입구를 점령하세요.
I heard from the Ximeng soldiers
Ximeng 영토를 우회하시겠습니까?
heading to mine in Mount Ximin today
시멍 병사들한테서 들었어
that although the area
오늘 시민산 광산으로 향 중
around the mine is a vast wilderness,
그 지역은
local hunters often go into the mountains to hunt
광산 주변은 광활한 황야야,
and have discovered several hidden paths in and out.
지역 사냥꾼 종종 사냥하러 산에 가네
As long as our men are divided into small teams
그리고 발견했습니다 들어오고 나가는 몇 가지 숨겨진 경로.
and successively sneak into these small paths
우리 남자들이 있는 한 작은 팀으로 나뉘어져
from within Ximeng territory,
그리고 차례로 몰래 들어와 이 작은 길들
we can enter the hinterland of Mount Heihe.
Ximeng 영토 내에서
The hinterland of Mount Heihe
우리는 배후지로 들어갈 수 있어요 헤이허산의
is not only difficult for the Great Yan Army to enter,
어려울 뿐만 아니라 대연군이 진입하려면,
but also for the Ximeng Army.
뿐만 아니라 Ximeng 군대에도 적용됩니다.
As long as we move fast enough,
충분히 빠르게 움직이면
we can catch them off guard
방심하지 않고 잡을 수 있어
and seize the black gold mine.
그리고 검은 금광을 탈취하세요.
Pass my order.
내 주문을 전달하세요.
Have Jing lead 2,000 Black Eagle Army soldiers
징을 가지고 흑수리군 병사 2,000명을 이끈다
to detour into Ximeng territory.
Ximeng 영토로 우회합니다.
So soon?
그럼 곧?
Based on my understanding of Chu,
Chu에 대한 나의 이해를 바탕으로
she definitely won't believe
그 사람은 절대 믿지 않을 거야
my reason for coming this time.
이번에 온 이유.
The longer we delay,
지연 시간이 길어질수록
the more prepared she and Zhuge Yue
그녀와 Zhuge Yue는 더 많이 준비할수록
will be.
될 것입니다.
Yes.
예.
Chu,
추,
don't blame me.
나를 비난하지 마십시오.
You said it yourself
당신이 직접 말했어요
that Great Yan was also once your home
그 Great Yan도 한때 당신의 집이었지요
and the people of Great Yan were also your people.
그리고 대연의 사람들 또한 당신의 사람들이었습니다.
Chu.
추.
These horses are the treasures of Great Yan.
이 말들 Great Yan의 보물입니다.
Although they may not look impressive,
비록 인상적이지는 않을지 모르지만,
they have a fierce temper.
그들은 성격이 사나워요.
I wonder if the horse tamers of Ximeng can tame them.
Ximeng의 말 조련사인지 궁금합니다. 그들을 길들일 수 있습니다.
If needed,
필요한 경우
I can send a few grooms from Great Yan
Great Yan에서 신랑 몇 명을 보낼 수 있어요
over to you.
당신에게.
The horse tamers of Ximeng all come from hunting backgrounds.
Ximeng의 말 조련사 모두 사냥 배경에서 나왔습니다.
Even fierce beasts in the mountains are nothing to them,
산속의 사나운 짐승이라도 그들에겐 아무것도 아니야
not to mention a few small
몇 가지 작은 것은 말할 것도 없고
but fierce wild horses from Great Yan.
그러나 Great Yan의 사나운 야생마.
Not necessarily.
반드시 그런 것은 아닙니다.
This little white Huolei horse
이 작고 하얀 Huolei 말
has a fierce temper.
성질이 급해요.
Even in Great Yan,
Great Yan에서도
no one can tame it.
누구도 그것을 길들일 수 없습니다.
You must be careful.
조심해야합니다.
Don't let it hurt you.
그것이 당신을 다치게 두지 마십시오.
I'd like to see
보고 싶어요
just how untamable this wild horse is.
이 야생마는 얼마나 길들여지지 않는지.
You lied to me?
나한테 거짓말했어요?
I picked this white horse especially for you.
나는 이 백마를 골랐다 특히 당신을 위해.
It is gentle and friendly.
온화하고 친절합니다.
Bad news!
나쁜 소식!
Lady Chu went to the horse ranch with Yan Xun.
Lady Chu는 말 목장에 갔습니다. 옌쉰과 함께.
And they've been there for half the day.
그리고 그들은 반나절 동안 거기에 있었습니다.
Even on horseback,
말을 타고도
they could have circled Ximengcheng 3 times by now.
그들은 Ximengcheng을 돌았을 수도 있습니다 지금까지 3번.
Aren't you going to check on them?
확인해보지 않을래?
The alliance between Ximeng and Great Yan is a state affair.
Ximeng 간의 동맹 Great Yan은 국정 문제입니다.
Xing is the Queen,
싱은 여왕이에요
so it's natural for her to do this.
그러니 그녀가 이렇게 하는 것은 자연스러운 일이다.
Impressive.
인상적인.
You're so calm.
당신은 정말 침착합니다.
This is the only place in Ximeng now where the flowers bloom.
지금 시멍에는 여기가 유일한 곳이에요 꽃이 피는 곳.
Chu,
추,
I keep dreaming
계속 꿈을 꾸고 있어
about what happened 7 years ago,
7년 전에 일어난 일에 대해
when my father was still alive
아버지가 아직 살아 계셨을 때
and everything was still as it was.
모든 것이 그대로였습니다.
I returned to Great Yan with you from Zhenhuangcheng.
나는 당신과 함께 Great Yan으로 돌아 왔습니다 진황성 출신.
We rode Huolei horses together on Mount Huihui
우리는 Huolei 말을 함께 탔습니다 희회산에서
and bathed in the hot springs.
그리고 온천에 몸을 담갔다.
I even took you to see my mother.
나는 심지어 당신을 어머니에게 데려갔습니다.
I told her,
내가 그녀에게 말했지
"Chu is
"츄는
the Heir Apparent's wife I chose."
내가 선택한 후계자의 아내입니다."
Just as I promised you
내가 약속한 대로
back in Qingshan Manor.
다시 Qingshan Manor로 돌아왔습니다.
As for the alliance between Great Yan and Ximeng,
동맹의 경우 Great Yan과 Ximeng 사이,
the protocol officials are already drafting a state communiqué.
프로토콜 관계자는 이미 국가 성명 초안 작성.
It will be finalized in a few days.
며칠 내로 최종 확정될 예정입니다.
You will be able to return to Great Yan very soon.
당신은 돌아올 수있을 것입니다 곧 Great Yan에게.
Are you asking me to leave?
나한테 떠나라고 하는 거야?
Yan Xun,
옌쉰,
we all have to move on.
우리 모두는 계속 나아가야 합니다.
You are my past,
너는 나의 과거야
but also my future.
하지만 내 미래도 마찬가지야.
I want to thank you.
나는 당신에게 감사하고 싶습니다.
Thank you for accompanying me in hell
지옥에서 나와 함께 해주셔서 감사합니다
for so many years.
수년 동안.
Thank you for not abandoning me
나를 버리지 않아서 고마워
in the darkest moments of my life.
내 인생의 가장 어두운 순간에.
Thank you for always standing by my side.
항상 내 옆에 있어줘서 고마워요.
If it weren't for you,
당신이 아니었다면
I, Yan Xun, would be nothing,
나 Yan Xun은 아무 것도 아닐 거예요,
and I would have died in the snowy night 7 years ago.
그리고 난 죽었을 거야 7년 전 눈 내리는 밤.
I won't say these things again.
나는 이런 말을 다시는 하지 않을 것이다.
I will make up for my mistakes with my whole life.
나는 내 실수를 만회할 것이다 내 평생 동안.
There are some things we don't need to say.
몇 가지가 있습니다 우리는 말할 필요가 없습니다.
We should understand each other.
우리는 서로를 이해해야 합니다.
Chu, you belong to me—
추, 넌 내 거야—
and only me.
그리고 나만.
I will protect you
내가 당신을 보호하겠습니다
and take you away.
그리고 당신을 데려가세요.
I took your hand 7 years ago
7년 전에 난 네 손을 잡았어
and never planned to let go.
그리고 절대 놓을 계획이 없었습니다.
Chu.
추.
Believe me.
나를 믿으세요.
Yan Xun.
옌쉰.
Right now,
지금은
the land of Great Yan is devastated,
Great Yan의 땅이 황폐화되었습니다.
and the people of Great Yan have nothing to eat.
그리고 대연의 사람들 먹을 것이 없습니다.
They need you more than I do.
나보다 그 사람들이 당신을 더 필요로 해요.
You shouldn't waste your time on me.
나한테 시간을 낭비하면 안 돼요.
I heard the new policy of Ximeng
Ximeng의 새로운 정책을 들었습니다
is welcomed by the people.
국민들의 환영을 받습니다.
My journey of thousands of miles here
나의 수천 마일의 여정은 여기까지
was not in vain.
헛되지 않았습니다.
Chu!
츄!
Trust me!
나를 믿으세요!
I will be a good king!
나는 좋은 왕이 될 것이다!
Yan Xun,
옌쉰,
I believe you.
나는 당신을 믿습니다.
I'm going out to run an errand.
나는 심부름을 하러 나갈 예정이다.
See? He couldn't stay put after all.
보다? 결국 그는 가만히 있을 수가 없었다.
You owe me a string of coins.
당신은 나에게 동전 한 뭉치를 빚지고 있어요.
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
The state communiqué
국가 성명
will be delivered to your residence tomorrow.
배달될 것이다 내일 네 집으로.
King of Great Yan, you can set your return date in advance.
대연왕(大燕王), 귀국 날짜를 미리 설정할 수 있습니다.
Young Master.
젊은 스승님.
Young Master,
젊은 스승님,
as you ordered,
주문하신 대로
I investigated the Faceless God Sect.
얼굴없는 신파를 조사해봤습니다.
[The Faceless God Sect is a recently emerged organization in Ximeng.]
[얼굴 없는 신파는 최근 Ximeng에서 조직이 등장했습니다.]
This organization
이 조직
[Its leader is said to be a mysterious saintess, whose true face has never been seen.]
[그 리더는 신비한 성녀라고 하는데, 그 사람의 진짜 얼굴은 한 번도 본 적이 없습니다.]
only recently appeared in Ximeng.
최근에야 Ximeng에 등장했습니다.
[The sect is very mysterious, with followers spread widely across various countries.]
[종파는 매우 신비하며 추종자들이 있습니다. 여러 나라에 널리 퍼졌습니다.]
[Among them, the largest number is found in Great Yong, where it first appeared.]
[그 중에서 가장 많은 수는 처음 등장한 그레이트용에서 발견됩니다.]
It is said the leader is a saintess,
리더가 성녀라고 하는데,
but no one has seen her true face.
하지만 그녀의 진짜 얼굴을 본 사람은 아무도 없습니다.
Besides Ximeng,
시멍 외에
are there believers anywhere else?
다른 곳에도 신자가 있나요?
There are some in every country.
나라마다 일부는 있습니다.
What about Great Yong?
그레이트 용은 어떻습니까?
Great Yong has the most, and it started there the earliest.
위대한 용은 가장 많은 것을 가지고 있고, 그리고 그것은 거기서 가장 일찍 시작되었습니다.
Ximeng has been implementing the new policy for 4 months.
Ximeng이 구현해왔습니다. 4개월간 새로운 정책을 시행합니다.
Great Yong should
위대한 용은
have already gathered this information.
이미 이 정보를 수집했습니다.
You mean...
그러니까...
it's related to Great Yong?
그레이트 용과 관련이 있나요?
Shiyi,
시이,
send someone to Biantang and give this to He Xiao.
사람을 비안탕으로 보내라 그리고 이것을 허샤오에게 주세요.
Yes.
예.
This way! This way!
이쪽으로! 이쪽으로!
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
Your Majesty,
폐하,
Lady Chu.
레이디 추.
This place was originally an abandoned mortuary.
이 곳은 원래 버려진 영안실.
Recently, the Faceless God Sect has arisen in the city,
최근에는 얼굴없는 신교가 도시에서 발생했습니다.
so these believers are using this place
그래서 이 신자들이 이곳을 이용하고 있는 것 같아요
as a gathering spot.
모임 장소로.
But somehow,
하지만 왠지
it suddenly exploded.
갑자기 폭발했어요.
Seventeen people were killed in the explosion.
열일곱명 폭발로 사망했습니다.
Now only a female believer is left alive.
이제 여성 신자만 살아남게 되었습니다.
She has already been detained in the backyard.
그녀는 이미 구금되었습니다 뒷마당에서.
I will go see this believer.
나는 이 신자를 만나러 갈 것이다.
I will go check on the surrounding commoners.
내가 가서 확인해볼게 주변 평민들.
Be careful.
조심하세요.
What's your name?
이름이 뭐에요?
Can you tell me
나에게 말해줄 수 있나요
what exactly happened during the explosion?
정확히 무슨 일이 일어났나요? 폭발 중에?
That was divine punishment from the Faceless God!
그건 신의 형벌이었어 얼굴없는 신으로부터!
Divine punishment?
신성한 형벌?
The people who died
죽은 사람들
were not true believers of the Faceless God at all.
그들은 참된 신자들이 아니었습니다 전혀 얼굴없는 신의.
Those chosen by the Faceless God
얼굴 없는 신에게 선택된 자들
cannot die at all.
전혀 죽을 수 없습니다.
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
This was the Faceless God filtering out the true believers.
이게 바로 얼굴없는 신이었어 참된 신자들을 걸러내는 것입니다.
Filtering out believers?
신자들을 걸러낸다?
I am the lucky one
나는 행운아야
chosen by the god.
신에 의해 선택되었습니다.
Then can you take me
그럼 나를 데려가 주실 수 있나요
to see your god?
너의 신을 만나러?
You foolish people
어리석은 사람들아
cannot see the Faceless God at all.
얼굴없는 신을 전혀 볼 수 없습니다.
The Faceless God will only appear
얼굴 없는 신은 오직 나타날 것이다
when she wants to.
그녀가 원할 때.
Let me out!
나를 내보내주세요!
I want to see my god!
나는 나의 신을 보고 싶다!
I just asked the people nearby.
근처 사람들에게 물어봤습니다.
They said
그들이 말하길
someone told them
누군가가 그들에게 말했어
the Saintess would appear here today
성녀가 오늘 여기에 나타날 거야
to worship the Faceless God.
얼굴 없는 신을 숭배하는 것.
So all the people in the city
그럼 도시에 있는 모든 사람들이
who wanted to worship the Saintess
성녀를 숭배하고 싶었던 사람
or the Faceless God came here.
아니면 얼굴없는 신이 여기에 왔거나.
But no one expected
하지만 아무도 예상하지 못했어
an explosion to happen.
폭발이 일어나게 됩니다.
What about you? Did you find out anything?
당신은 어때요? 뭔가 알아냈어?
She said she was chosen by the Faceless God,
그녀는 자신이 선택되었다고 말했다 얼굴 없는 신에 의해,
and the Faceless God will come to see her.
그러면 얼굴 없는 신이 그녀를 보러 올 것이다.
You may leave.
떠날 수도 있습니다.
Minglu.
밍루.
Stay here and watch her tonight.
오늘 밤 여기 머물면서 그녀를 지켜보세요.
Ensure her safety,
그녀의 안전을 보장해 주세요
but don't let her notice you.
하지만 그녀가 당신을 알아차리지 못하게 하세요.
Yes.
예.
Well? Any news?
잘? 어떤 소식이 있나요?
I followed her all night.
나는 밤새도록 그녀를 따라갔습니다.
After she returned home yesterday, she stayed inside and never came out.
어제 집에 돌아온 후, 그녀는 안에 머물렀고 결코 나오지 않았습니다.
And this morning,
그리고 오늘 아침에는
she washed up, changed her clothes, and left the house around 9 AM,
그녀는 씻고, 옷을 갈아입고, 그리고 오전 9시쯤 집을 떠났어요
wearing that yellow silk handkerchief on her wrist
그 노란 비단 손수건을 입고 손목에
and heading to the South Market.
그리고 사우스마켓으로 향합니다.
A yellow silk handkerchief?
노란 비단 손수건?
Yes.
예.
It's the same yellow silk handkerchief
똑같은 노란색 실크 손수건이야
we previously saw on the wrists
이전에 손목에 있는 걸 본 적이 있어
of commoners who follow the Saintess.
Saintess를 따르는 평민의.
I suspect this is their secret signal.
나는 이것이 그들의 비밀 신호라고 생각합니다.
I had Xiao Ran follow her
Xiao Ran이 그녀를 따라오도록 했어요
and hurried back to report.
그리고 서둘러 보고를 했습니다.
Tell Meng En to bring a few men.
맹은에게 사람 몇 명을 데려오라고 말하세요.
Let's go take a look.
보러 가자.
Okay.
좋아요.
These reports
이 보고서
were gathered from the checkpoints
were gathered from the checkpoints
bordering Ximeng and Great Yan.
검문소에서 수집되었습니다
They shouldn't be wrong.
Ximeng과 Great Yan과 접해 있습니다.
Have Yan Xun and the Great Yan delegation
그들은 틀려서는 안됩니다.
been in Ximengcheng this whole time?
Yan Xun과 Great Yan 대표단이 있습니다
Yes.
내내 Ximengcheng에 있었나요?
Since entering Ximengcheng,
예.
they have been staying at the posthouse in the western part of the city
Ximengcheng에 들어간 이후
and haven't gone out.
그들은 우체국에 머물고 있어요 도시 서쪽에
Your Majesty,
그리고 아직 안 나갔어.
King Ximeng...
폐하,
It seems you guessed I would come.
내가 올 거라고 짐작한 것 같군요.
You're just in time.
시간이 딱 맞춰 왔네요.
Come and taste this pheasant soup.
와서 이 꿩 수프를 맛보세요.
It's a golden pheasant I brought specially from Great Yan.
황금꿩이에요 Great Yan에서 특별히 가져왔습니다.
It won't taste good if it gets cold.
식으면 맛이 없을 것 같아요.
Bad news!
나쁜 소식!
Lady Chu is now a princess of Great Yong?
추부인은 이제 대용의 공주가 되었나요?
All our past ties
우리의 과거 인연
are now in vain.
이제 헛된 것입니다.
Did it all start
모든 게 시작됐나요
because of you?
너 때문에?
If it dies,
죽으면
I will kill you!
나는 당신을 죽일 것입니다!
I am you, and you are me.
나는 당신이고 당신은 나입니다.
I am Chu Qiao.
저는 추차오(Chu Qiao)입니다.
We will be an ordinary couple,
우리는 평범한 커플이 될 거예요
traveling around
여행 중
and living a free and unrestrained life.
자유롭고 제한받지 않는 삶을 살아갑니다.